hey guys uh check out this message
called justification by faith and the
cleansing of the sanctuary it is dealing
with this theme of Christ's
righteousness and how it relates to the
investigative judgment you're going to
be blessed by it so stay
tuned
[Music]
I want to invite you uh to turn with me
um if you have your Bibles um to the
Book of Revelation chapter 14 as we
again uh focus on the subject of
justification by
faith and the cleansing of the
sanctuary so we're going to go to the
screen Revelation chap 14 and verse 6
Revelation CH 14 and verse 6 the Bible
says here and I saw another angel fly in
the midst of Heaven
having the Everlasting gospel to preach
unto them that dwell on the earth and to
every nation and Kindred and tongue and
people saying with a loud voice fear God
and give glory to him for the hour of
his judgment is come and worship him
that made Heaven and Earth and the Sea
and The Fountains of water in Revelation
14: 6 and 7 we are
told that the hour of his judgment is
come this signifies that there is a
judgment to take place on Earth before
the second coming of Christ to verify
this we'll go to the next verse which is
revelation
14:12 and in Revelation 14:12 the Bible
says here is the patience of the Saints
here are they that keep the Commandments
of God and the faith of Jesus and then
one verse later two verses later the
Bible says this and I looked and behold
a white cloud and upon the cloud one sat
like unto the son of man having on his
head a Golden Crown and in his hand a
sharp sickle and another angel came out
of the temple crying with a loud voice
to him that sat on the cloud thrust in
thy sickle and
reap for the time has come for for thee
to reap for the Harvest of the earth is
ripe and he that sat on the cloud thrust
in his sickle on the Earth and the Earth
was
reaped what we get from these verses is
the fact that Pro that judgment begins
sometime before Jesus returns to reap
the
Earth to reap the
Harvest and so
as we set this Foundation to help us to
understand that there is in fact a
judgment prior to the second coming of
Christ we we can see this same theme in
the Book of Daniel chapter 8 and verse
13 in Daniel chapter 8 verse verse 13
Daniel is is is is in
vision and he's watching a series of
events unfold which culminate with a
question the Bible says in verse 13 then
I heard one Saint
speaking and another Saint said unto
that certain Saint which speak how long
shall be the vision concerning the daily
sacrifice and the transgression of
desolation to give both the sanctuary
and the host to be trotten underfoot and
the answer comes back unto 2300 days or
unto
2,300 days
then shall the sanctuary be cleansed now
we're not going to take time to break
down this particular time prophecy
because that is not the focus of the
message
today what I do want to illustrate is
that this verse is speaking of the same
judgment that is spoken of in Revelation
CH
14 when Daniel hears the term uh the
sanctuary shall be cleansed it is point
ing back to an Old Testament Feast Day
known as the day of atonement and please
note with me in re in Le in The Book of
Leviticus 16:
29 and verse 30 the Bible says speaking
of this day of atonement a day in which
the sanctuary was cleansed it says this
shall be a statute for you uh forever
unto you that in the seventh month on
the 10th day of the month you shall
afflict your souls and do no work at all
whether it be one of your own or a
stranger that is among you for on that
day shall the priest make an atonement
for you to cleanse you that you may be
clean from all your sins before the
Lord what I want you to understand about
this day of atonement is that it was
considered the day of judgment uh to the
Hebrews to the Jews they understood this
day as referring the cleansing of the
sanctuary as referring to a judgment and
so if we put all this together so far
what we have being described in
Revelation chapter 14 is this judgment
that is to occur that is synonymous with
the cleansing of the sanctuary that in
some way pointed to the actual cleansing
of the
individual the Judgment was designed not
to destroy but to cleanse
and purify the people of God if you're
with me so far put a one in the chat
we're going to move on to the Book of
Daniel we're going to go back to the
Book of Daniel and we're going to see
the same scene being described in a
different way Daniel chapter 7 verse 9
and 10 the Bible says and I beheld till
the Thrones were cast down and the
Ancient of Days did sit whose garment
was white as snow and the hair of his
head like the pure wool his throne was
like the fiery flame and his wheels as
burning
fire a fiery stream issued and came
forth from before him thousand thousands
ministered unto him and 10,000 time
10,000 stood before him and now note
these words the Judgment was
set and the books were
opened Daniel in vision is giving us one
of the most descriptive pictures of this
judgment that is to occur before the
second coming of Christ in this judgment
he says the books are opened and there
are thousands thousands around God's
Throne angels that are T taking part in
this
judgment and so what we understand is
that this judgment contains a record a
record of the lives of all who are going
to be involved in this judgment
process that means if you profess Christ
your name is coming up in this judgment
if you claim to follow uh Christ your
name is going to come up in this
judgment now I don't know about you but
if you've ever been in a court room
before and you know that there is a
record there is a record that that that
contains your actions for whatever it is
you're in court for and there's a record
that contains your actions and if you
are guilty you're probably going to be
very very
nervous why because if you're guilty if
you're guilty and there is a
record that is all the evidence that is
needed to put you
away well in this same way the Bible
says that there are books or records
that are going to be involved in this
judgment the books plural were opened
now I got a question for you how many of
you would like to know ahead of time
what's in your
record Put put a one in the chat if you
feel like man it would help it would
really help if if I could get a sneak
peek at the record my record put a one
in the chat if if you think man that
would I I would really like that I would
really like to know because if I know
what's in the records hold on y if I
know what's in the
record okay now I got something to let
you know beloved I have something to let
you know that is going to blow your mind
and it is this the Bible says in Psalm
139:23 note with me Psalm 139:23 the
Bible says search me now in the Judgment
God is looking at your life God is
searching you let's go back to the
screen let's read what it says sir
search me oh God and know my heart try
me and know my thoughts and see if there
be any wicked way in me and Lead Me in
the way Everlasting in other words
beloved God in the judgment is searching
your heart you are the thing he is
searching you are the thing you are the
book he is
reading put a five in the chat if you
understand what I just shared
in this investigative judgment when the
books are open the reason these books
are plural is because the books are the
people the people are the
books you are the book that God is
searching now please note that God is
not searching for himself as if he
doesn't already know but but it is the
angels that are around the throne and
all the Heavenly hosts who cannot read
the
heart and so the books are open for
Angels now why is it so important to
understand because according to the book
of uh um of of uh Jeremiah 17:1 the
Bible says this the sin of Judah is
written with a pen of iron and the point
and with the point of a diamond it is
Graven upon the table of their heart and
upon the horns of your altars in other
words
beloved every sin that we have ever
committed is recorded in
us it is recorded in
us
we are the books
listen listen listen Romans Chapter 2
just just to demonstrate Romans chapter
2 verse 14 and 15 for when the Gentiles
which have not the law do by Nature the
things contained in the law these having
not the law are a law unto themselves
which show the work of the law
written in their hearts their conscience
also bearing witness and their thoughts
the mean while accusing or else
excusing one another how about this one
how about this second Corinthians
chapter 3: 2 and 3 where the Bible says
you are our
epistle written in our hearts known and
read of all men for as much as you are
manifestly declared to be the Epistle of
Christ ministered by US Written not with
ink but with the spirit of the Living
God not in tables of stone but in fleshy
tables of the heart what I'm trying to
demonstrate to you today
beloved is that you are the
book and if you are the book guess what
you already have access to the
[Music]
book y'all put a seven in the chat if
you understand what I just said you
don't need to guess what's in the book
because you are already know what's in
the book why because you are the
book now there may be things you forgot
was in the book but when God brings them
up and when go if you should be lost and
God says you remember this you're not
going to be like no I don't remember
that that never happened you're going to
remember it because it was
recorded are y'all with
me you are the book now beloved listen
to me this is good news let me tell you
why let me tell you why Psalm 26:2 says
this examine me oh Lord and prove me try
my Reigns and my heart God is saying I
want you to invite me to examine your
life to examine your
book invite me that's what we're called
to do Lord search my heart search this
book now what's in what what is in every
book
y'all what's in a book what makes a book
A book there's something in
it it's
words it's
words all books are going to have words
that describe the content of the book
come on diamond do not jump ahead of me
sir do not not jump ahead of me sir why
are you doing this right now Diamond no
one look at Diamond's
comment no one look at Diamond's comment
at least not yet not yet now watch this
not only does God say uh uh um I want to
examine your book and I'm going to
examine you but we are also encouraged
in second Corinthians chap
13:5 examine yourselves whether you be
in the faith prove your own selves know
you not your own selves how that Jesus
Christ is in you except you be
reprobated so in other words we are told
that we we can examine oursel you can
examine your book right
now now let me ask you a question
y'all how many of you would like your
book to be ready for
judgment how many of you would like your
book to be ready for judge so that when
God is looking at your book he is well
pleased how many of you would like that
put a five in the chat if you would like
to have your book ready for
examination now now please I'm about to
tie this in with something so you can
understand here you see in the Old
Testament in the Old Testament Sanctuary
right the place that the Judgment was to
take place in the Old Testament in the
Old Testament Sanctuary what would
happen is that when a person sinned they
would confess their sins over the head
of a l and and by by faith that sin the
record of the sin was transferred from
The Sinner to the lamb and then the lamb
was killed and the blood was taken into
the sanctuary the blood containing the
record of the sin was brought into the
sanctuary
meaning the the record of sin was placed
in the temple the record of sin was
placed in the temple now note what the
Bible says in 1 Corinthians 6: 19 it
says this know you not that your body is
the Temple of the Holy Ghost which you
have of God and you are not your own so
if I can say it this way beloved in the
Old Testament the
sanctuary that was to be cleansed was a
symbol of the cleansing of the
individual and the fact that the record
of sin was in the temple so we
understand that the record of our sin
the record of Our Lives is
in the
temple the
temple so so with this in mind we now
can begin to understand that in this
investigative judgment which is designed
to cleanse the record of sin what God is
ultimately saying is I am Desiring to
cleanse your record to cleanse your book
the book of your life
now how many of you how many of you when
you look at your book when you look at
your book you start to get a little
worried you start to
fear let me tell you why why we should
all be afraid when we look at our books
let me show you why let's go to the Book
of Romans chap 5:12 because in our books
all of us have the story of condemnation
wherefore Romans 5:12 wherefore as by
one man sin entered into the world and
death by sin and so death passed upon
all men for that all have sinned notice
with me Romans 2 Romans 3:23 for all
have sinned and come short of the glory
of God that's the story of our books
that's the story of our books before we
meet Christ the story of our
book is condemnation in fact let me read
to you another verse that well describes
the stories of our books the Bible says
in Romans 3:1 as it is written there is
none righteous know not one there is
none that understandeth there is none
that seeketh after God they are all gone
out of the way they are all together
become unprofitable there is none that
doeth good no not one their throat isn't
open separer with their tongues they
have used deceit the poison of asps is
under their lips whose mouth is full of
cursing and bitterness their feet are
Swift to shed destruction destruction or
shed blood the destruction and misery
are in their ways and the way of peace
they have not known there is no fear of
God Before Their Eyes now we
know that whatsoever things the law
saith it saith to them who are under the
law that every mouth may be stopped and
all the world become
guilty become
guilty before God
therefore by the Deeds of the the law
shall no flesh be justified in his sight
for by the law is the knowledge of sin
so come back with me y'all do y'all get
the picture here every one of us when we
open our books what we see is
condemnation condemnation condemnation
condemnation condemnation that's what we
see and that's why everybody at least
initially needs to be worried about the
Judgment because you already know what's
in your
book you already know what's
there why because you have access to the
book you know the
story the words in your
book only point of
condemnation so now the question is what
do I do listen if I have access to the
book then maybe huh
if I have access to the book then is
there a way that I can change what's in
the
book come on
y'all is there a way that I
can control alt
delete that I can erase that I can that
I
can tear out
Pages well listen remember the cleansing
of the
sanctuary points to the cleansing of the
individual the cleansing of the
book The cleansing of the record of sin
so my question is okay all right what
can I do to cleanse my book what can I
do to cleanse all those things that I've
done in the past all how can I rewrite
how can I exchange the those bad words
for good words check this out y'all
Psalm 119 notice with me Psalm 119 verse
9 wherewith o shall a young man cleanse
his
way how can I be cleansed how can I
cleanse my book how can I cleanse the
record oh the Bible says by taking heed
according to Thy word oh wait a minute
so take heed to God's
word then you mean I can use I can
exchange the old words the old words in
my book can be exchanged purified if I
take heed to God's word h so you mean I
can exchange the old words for new
word wow wow you mean
yes Jamie I I can have a new author and
finisher of my
book okay okay so if I just take heed
according to the word well what is the
word what is the word come back with me
to John chap 1:14 where the Bible says
and the Word was made flesh and dwelt
among us and we beheld his glory the
glory as of the only begotten of the
father full of grace and truth okay wait
a minute so Pastor what you're telling
me is that if if I have Christ who is
the word invited into me then what he
does is he exchanges the old words for
himself are y'all with
me yes doc it points back to cist if if
I can get Christ in
me if Christ is in me then a new word is
in me that is overpowering and in fact
erasing the old words of the
book why in fact in Psalm 11 19111 the
Bible says listen to this Thy word have
I hid in my heart that I might not sin
against thee wow all right all right I'm
following you Pastor if if if I have
Jesus hidden in my heart then he does
something miraculous which which somehow
eliminates the sin in my heart yes Marco
I like that we get a new
history we get a new past now watch this
why do I want this because remember in
my book my book says
condemnation but I don't want
condemnation in the Judgment what do I
want in the what is the opposite of
condemnation all right come on let's
find out let's find out Romans Chapter 5
Verse 18 the Bible says but now the
righteousness of God without the law is
manifested being witnessed by the law
and the prophets even the righteousness
of God which is by faith of Jesus Christ
unto all and upon all them that believe
for there is no difference for all have
sinned and come short of the glory of
God being justified freely by his grace
through the Redemption that is in Christ
Jesus whom God set forth remember those
words set forth to be a propitiation
through faith in his blood to declare
the righteousness for the remission of
sins that are passed through the
forbearance of God to declare I say at
this time his
righteousness that he might be just and
the justifier of him which believeth in
him where is boasting then it is
excluded by what law of Works nay but by
the law of Faith therefore we conclude
that a man is justified by faith without
the Deeds of the law so here's what I
want you to understand the text just
told us that that the law points to our
condemnation and that's why we have
condemned condemned condemn written in
the book
but if I accept Christ he comes into my
life and justifies which is the opposite
of condemnation justifies yes GG just as
if I never
sinned his blood justifies or takes away
my past sin in effect rewriting my
history so that when God opens the books
he's like oh look at this look at this
look at
this because he sees Christ life in the
place of your
life there was a
transfer of the word to your
book so when the word came into your
book The Old words were done away with
the old words were gone that condem
ation is done away with why because the
new word is in your
book are y'all with me so far beloved
we're going to come right back to the
sanctuary and I need you to understand
this because this is absolutely end time
crucial watch this watch this in 1
Corinthians chapter 15:6 the Bible says
the sting of death is sin and the
strength of sin is the law so I want you
to think about it like this if
if the sting of death is sin so so
imagine being
bitten by
sin and then that sin works like a Venom
in your body that brings about
death why is this crucial to
understand well you
see what we need to understand here
beloved is that if the sanctuary was a
symbol of how God eliminates Sin from
you then what he is showing
us is that just as in the Old Testament
there was a process in the sanctuary
that removed the venom out of the out of
the temple so Christ in his closing work
is doing the same he is seeking to
remove the Venom of the serpent from our
bodies put a five in the chat if you're
following me the sanctuary is a symbol
of God of of of the
individual through whom God is working
to ultimately remove Sin from the temple
the poison of sin The Sting of sin now
why have I done all this set up I've
done all this St to bring you back
beloved to a very powerful and
lifechanging story in the Old Testament
which is this numbers
21:5 and the people spake against God
and against Moses wherefore have you
brought us up up out of Egypt to die in
the wilderness for there is no bread
neither is there any water and our soul
loatheth this light bread and the Lord
sent fiery serpents among the people and
they bit the people people and much
people of Israel died therefore the
people came to Moses and said we have
sinned the Venom of sin is flowing
through our veins right now Moses what
shall we do to get rid of this Venom
this Venom of sin that is flowing in our
bodies in our temples what shall we
do Moses prayed for the people and the
Lord said unto Moses make thee a fiery
Serpent and set it on a pole remember
what we just read in Romans Jesus was
set forth as a PR propitiation for our
sin what is numbers telling us here make
the fiery Serpent and set it on a
pole and it shall come to pass that
everyone that is bitten everyone that
has venom flowing through their veins
when he lookth upon
it when he lookth upon it shall live
beloved this is the essence of the
Gospel it is exactly what John the
Baptist said when he saw Jesus the next
day John seeth Jesus coming unto him and
saith
what
Behold the Lamb of God that gets into
your book and removes the sins from your
book Behold the Lamb of God which taketh
away the sin of the world now beloved
I'm about to tell tell you something
that I've been saying for the last
several weeks now and it is very
simple the way the sanctuary is cleansed
is by beholding the Lamb of
God the way we make it through the
judgment is by beholding the Lamb of
God that is it you
all if we Behold the Lamb of God Cor
directly not just
glance if we Behold the Lamb of God
correctly there will be a series of
events that that flow naturally as a
result this is the judgment is simply
about who is beholding the Lamb of God
and who
isn't listen to this
let's go to the screen this is from
Marin page 99 listen to this y'all will
Marin page 99 will not our church
members keep their eyes fixed on a
crucified and Risen Savior in whom their
hopes of of eternal life are
centered this is our
message our argument our Doctrine our
warning to the impenitent our
encouragement for The Sorrowing the hope
for every
believer if we can awaken an interest in
men's Minds that will cause them to fix
their eyes on Christ we may step aside
pause for a second y'all come back with
come back come back come back with for
AE she is saying here if we can get
people to just fix their eyes on Christ
to fix their focus on the Lamb of God to
fix their focus on the serpent on the
pole she says we can step aside hey get
out the way are you looking just get out
the way just step aside so once they're
looking step aside because God has it
from here God H if we can just get them
let's go back to the screen if we can
awaken an interest in men's Minds that
will cause them to fix their eyes on in
Christ we may step aside and ask them
only only put that word in the chat for
me please ask them only please I need to
see that word only in the chat and make
it all cap locks we we may step aside
and ask them only to continue to fix
their eyes upon the Lamb of God he whose
Eyes Are Fixed On Jesus will leave all
he will die to selfishness he
will believe in all the word of God
which is so gloriously and wonderfully
exalted in Christ did y'all see that
just
[Music]
now did y'all see what we just read just
now
if we can show others Christ and and and
and only asked them hey keep looking
keep fixing your Gaze on the serpent on
the pole the result is they will
live they will hey so how'd you make it
to Heaven
well I just
beheld not hey how'd you get to heaven
man I did this I did that I was helping
people no no no no no how did you get to
heaven I beheld the Lamb of God how' you
get through the Judgment I beheld the
Lamb of God y'all understand what I'm
saying it is in beholding the Lamb of
God that power is released from Heaven
that enables us to walk in
righteousness nothing else not our own
efforts not our own strength it is by
beholding the Lamb of God so this is why
this is why the Bible tells us in John
chapter 6 verse 53 Jesus then Jesus said
unto them verily verily I say unto you
except you eat the Flesh of the son of
man and drink his blood you have no life
in you who so eateth my flesh and
drinketh my blood has eternal life and I
will raise him up at the last day what
does Jesus mean what does Jesus mean
when he says except you eat my flesh and
drink my blood what is he talking about
he's talking about his death he's
talking about the very thing that was s
symbolized by the serpent on the pole so
what he's saying is what does it mean
why is he saying you need my flesh and
my blood why is he saying that you need
to focus on my death in your life why
listen to this y'all because according
to Leviticus 17:1 the life of the
flesh is in the
blood let me say it again the life of
the flesh is in the blood
so in this case who is the flesh we're
talking about the flesh we're talking
about is
Jesus are are y'all with
me the life of Jesus is in his blood and
without the shedding of blood there is
no remission of sin so if I want the
life of Jesus I need his blood I need
his
sacrifice I need to eat that now how am
I going to eat the sacrifice of Christ
how I going to eat the the Flesh and
body or blood of Christ how am I going
to do that what does it mean to eat help
help me y'all what does it mean to eat
something give me another word for
eat I like that GG grazing
upon grazing upon
consume
digest not just swallow you need to eat
you need to F you need to to digest this
thing you need to consume you need to
focus in you need to meditate the Bible
says in Matthew chapter 4 verse4 listen
to what it says here it says man shall
not live by bread alone but by every
word that proceedeth out of the mouth of
God every word that proceedeth out of
the mouth of God so the more we behold
listen when we are digesting the word of
God when we're digesting the Flesh and
the body of the of Christ which means
his sacrifice it's in it's another way
of saying look at the serpent on the
pole and keep
looking why because according to 2
Corinthians 3:18 the Bible says but we
all with open face beholding as in a
glass the glory of the Lord are changed
into the same image from glory to glory
even as by the spirit of the the Lord do
y'all understand the more we look at
what Jesus did for us on the cross is
the more we are changed into that
image the more we behold and focus upon
and devour and meditate on Christ's Act
of sacrifice on the
cross the
deeper our connection with him becomes
and while that connection is happening
Venom is leaving our body just as those
who were bitten by the serpent when they
looked the power of the Venom was
removed listen to me y'all this is why
this is why we are told in in the Desire
of Ages page 83 it would be well for us
to spend a thoughtful hour every day in
contemplation of The Life of
Christ we should take it Point by point
and let the imagination grasp each scene
especially the closing
ones as we thus dwell upon his great
sacrifice for us watch this y'all our
confidence in him will be more constant
our love will be quickened we shall be
more deeply imbued with his Spirit if we
will be saved at last we must learn the
lesson of penitence and humiliation at
the foot of the cross do y'all
understand why it would be well for us
to spend at least an hour every day
meditating upon his life especially the
closing scenes it is because beloved by
looking and contemplating and
beholding we become changed you want to
are you afraid of the Judgment so you're
afraid of the judgment all right man I
need to start doing this and start doing
God no no no you need to focus on being
justified by faith in Christ how does
that happen
look just
look if you look I will take care of the
Venom if you focus I will take care of
the Venom I will remove the sin out of
your system I will remove the sin out of
your temple your temple the sanctuary
will be cleansed but I need you to keep
looking at what I did for you on the
cross this is why Beloved the Bible says
in Psalm
77:13 thy way oh God is in the sanctuary
who is so great a god what does it mean
thy way is in the sanctuary thy way oh
God is in the sanctuary Jesus said I am
the way the truth and the life so if
Jesus said I am the way the truth and
the life then what he's saying is I if
you look in the sanctuary I am there I
am the way that is in that Sanctuary so
so if you have ever studied the
sanctuary you will see
beloved you will see that in the
sanctuary there are six articles of
furniture and those six articles of
furniture are literally found in the
shape of the Cross meaning beloved that
the Sanctuary is God's x-ray vision of
the cross it is his x-ray vision of the
serpent on the pole in other words if
you want to know how the cross works you
look at the sanctuary and you will see
the mechanics in those articles of
furniture you see the mechanics of how
the cross works all right y'all seven in
the chat if y'all caught what I just
said inside the
sanctuary the system that God set up to
show man how you are cleansed from your
sins the cross is front and center in
the sanctuary these articles of
furniture are in fact an x-ray vision of
the Cross it's showing you the mechanics
inside the CR hey how does that computer
work well let me pull the computer apart
and show you all the parts of the
computer that make if you want know how
the cross Works beloved if you want to
know how the cross works you look at the
sanctuary you look at these articles of
furniture and you begin to see ah so
when I'm beholding the cross what I'm
actually beholding is these principles
that are found that show us the the
Latasha the the the the sanctuary is the
blueprint of the
Cross and so what happens is as we're
beholding Christ if we're beholding him
right we know what's going to happen
those articles of furniture and the
things that they represent the altar of
sacrifice and the labor and the table of
showbread and the altar of incense and
the Seven Branch candles stick and the
Ark of the Covenant and The Mercy Seat
these things become actualities in our
lives why because we are beholding the
serpent on the pole we are beholding
Christ in his sacrifice now I need y'all
to catch this because when we behold
Jesus two things in particular are going
to happen for us are you ready two
things in particular are going to happen
for us if we rightly behold Christ let's
go here it is according to Hebrews chap
1:8 the Bible says but unto the son unto
the son he saith thy Throne oh God is
forever and ever a scepter of
righteousness is the scepter of thy
kingdom now watch this speaking of Jesus
it say says Thou Hast loved
righteousness and hated iniquity
therefore God even thy God has anointed
thee with the oil of gladness above thy
fellows beloved when we behold Jesus the
two things that stick out about Jesus is
that he loved righteousness and hated
iniquity so if I behold Jesus right and
by beholding we become changed I am
going to begin to love righteousness and
what hate
iniquity those are two different things
I I want you to think of it like this
let's go to the screen to hate
iniquity is to hate transgressing the
law it is hating the things that the
law
prohibits right it is in a sense
it is saying I I
despise
wrong I despise breaking the law but
righteousness is actually positive
action it is it is being kind to others
it is it is feeding the hungry you know
the the poor it is De it is doing good
acts unto others so so so listen it is
not enough for for us to just hate
iniquity or just hey I don't lie I don't
steal you cannot do those things and
still not be
righteous or you can do righteous acts
but do these things you must have both
if you want to think about it like this
think of it like this there are sins of
commission and sins of
omission sins of commission are hey I'm
breaking the law by lying stealing
killing Etc you're committing acts of
sin but there's also sins of omission
yeah you know what uh I see that guy
beat up on the side of the road I'm on
my way to Jericho eh I don't I'm you
know let somebody else deal with
that no I'm not going to help that
person no I'm not going to be not sins
of omission sins of commission when we
behold Jesus beloved he changes Us in
character so that we learn learn to hate
iniquity and we learn to love
righteousness come on let me break it
down for you let me break it down for
you come on let's go to the screen so
the altar of sacrifice you see when we
behold what Jesus did on the cross for
us when we actually take time and stop
daily and say Lord today help my focus
to be looking at the serpent on the pole
to be looking at Christ and what he did
for us something begins to happen
beloved as you slowly contemplate the
cross because what begins to happen is
that you will begin to get a hatred for
sin because of what it did to Jesus
because sin put the Lamb of God to death
altar of sacrifice because sin put
Christ on the cross you begin to hate
sin because of what it did to Jesus you
begin to hate it was your defilement
that brought about the death of Jesus it
was our neglect of the word of God that
brought the death of Jesus we begin to
hate that which is not in accordance
with the word of God why because of what
that very act because of that that is
the thing that put Christ on the cross
we begin to hate coldness the the the
seven Branch Candlestick which was a
symbol of fire we begin to hate coldness
and lukewarmness why that's what put
Jesus on the cross our coldness towards
God our lukewarmness towards God we
begin to hate these
things that brought about the separate
my God my God why hast Thou forsaken me
when we look at Jesus on the cross
everything that these articles of
furniture represent the law of God it
was because of our sin that he left his
throne in heaven beloved we begin to
hate those things that are we hate
unforgiveness because it demonstrate it
is demonstrated at the cross Christ
forgave us how can we not forgive others
we begin to hate listen to me the more
we Behold the Lamb of God on the cross
the things that put him
there
sin
defilement cold Hearts A neglect of the
word those things we will begin to
naturally hate put a five in the chat if
you're following me but not only does
the cross instill a hate and enmity in
us against sin and against the things
that cause the death of Jesus beloved it
also puts love in our hearts let's go
back to the screen let's go back to the
screen it also puts love in our hearts
because now as we are beholding that
serpent on the pole as we're beholding
the Lamb of God we are in
awe of his sacrifice that's the altar of
sacrifice we are in awe of his Purity
that's the labor he died for us he died
taking the sins of the world upon him
and yet he had no sin what we are in awe
of his faithfulness to the word of God
we are in awe of his connection with his
father he prayed daily he did everything
to stay connected with him and we are in
awe of his fiery passion the seven
Branch Candlestick we in all of his
fiery passion for us so much so that he
was willing to die we are in awe of his
obedience to the law of God and we are
in awe of his mercy and
beloved I you you know the saying a
picture is worth a thousand words all we
need do is look at that picture of the
serpent on the pole the Lamb of God
which taketh away the sins of the world
and if we rightly read the picture and
sit there and just behold and behold and
behold what I'm saying let this whole
year be dedicated to beholding the Lamb
of God let me study this sacrifice like
I have never studied it before in my
prayer time let me meditate on that
picture Lord speak to me transform me as
I look at that
picture and let my imagination grasp
that scene and the more we do that the
Lord says yes Dr mcfar we must become
obsessed with that sacrif
sacrifice and the more we focus on that
picture and the words begin to pop out
look at that man of God look at that
definition of a man look at that courage
look at that faithfulness look at that
love look at that fiery passion as he
hangs there on the cross for us Lord
please transform me into that image
transform me into that individual that I
am so admiring right now
Transform Me
Lord and then
beloved then that's when this
happens you see look at the
screen the more we
behold not only the picture of his
hatred for
sin but also the picture of his love for
righteousness something begins to happen
in US it produces
reactionary
righteousness we talked about this in
the message justification by faith and
the mark of the beast righteousness is a
reaction it is not an action it is a
reaction and as we're beholding this
picture of Christ on the cross this
righteous reaction begins to happen in
us and here's what it does it grants us
power it grants us power
I like that reflection righteousness I
love that reflection righteousness
meaning I am simply reacting and
reflecting what I am seeing on the cross
you know you take that mirror this the
sun is coming down from the you take
that mirror and you put it up to the Sun
and then this the light just it's the
same light you become the mirror you're
the mirror that is reflecting what
happened on the cross and as you become
that mirror woo the glory of the Lord
lightens the Earth because of his
reflective
disciples who who get the secret wait a
minute it's not in me exerting my
physical my power to try to be righteous
if listen if I focus on the Lamb of God
if I focus on Calvary which is our
message our argument our Doctrine our
our our hope to the to the if we f focus
on that thing we we we turn into
mirrors we turn into mirrors and as
mirrors we begin to reflect the glory of
God the beautiful rays of light we begin
to and that light as is happening in me
and in you and the next person this is
what begins to lighten the Earth with
the glory of God it is his disciples
reflecting righteousness not trying to
produce produce righteousness in which
there is no light but reflecting
righteousness and so beloved watch this
as we begin to understand this I like
I'm I'm going to call this the seven
powers of the Cross here's what they are
the seven powers of the Cross is number
one power over the fear of death that's
the altar of sacrifice listen we're
almost there we're almost done watch
this here for as much then as the
children are partakers of Flesh and
Blood he also himself likewise took part
of the same that through death he might
destroy him that had the power of death
that is the devil and deliver them who
through fear of death were all their
lifetime subject to bondage I need y'all
to understand
this the more we behold Christ's
boldness on the cross that he was
willing to face death that he was
willing to die because of his love for
us there is a boldness that begins to be
birthed in US to the point where we no
longer fear
death God gives us power over the fear
of death the longer we behold Christ at
Calvary the stronger the Bolder we
become even in the face of death God
says I'm going to deliver you from that
fear of death the altar of sacrifice
when we behold Christ at the cross he
will grant us power over the fear of
death he will grant us power over not
only power over death but he will grant
us power over life that bra that altar
that labor beloved represented New Birth
a new life God says not only will I give
you power over death I will give you
power over life meaning watch this
meaning I am crucified with Christ why
because I've been looking at him at the
cross what happened to him happened the
way I am crucified with Christ is by
looking at his crucifixion
and as we look at his crucifixion we
become what we see we become what we are
eating what the mind is feeding upon our
minds are to be feeding upon the
sacrifice the Flesh and the blood of
Christ
continually so the text says I am
crucified with Christ nevertheless I
live yet not I but Christ lives in me
and the life which I now live in the
flesh I live by the faith of the Son of
God I'm justified by the faith of the
Son of God who loved me and gave himself
for me so not only do we begin to get
power over death not only do we begin to
get power over life I'm living a new
life we begin to get power beloved over
sight come with me to the screen power
over sight power over sight that's a
table of showbread what is a table of
show represent it represents the word of
God the Bible says man shall not live by
bread alone but by every word that
proceeds out of the mouth of God the
Bible says that the
just Hebrews chap 10:38 now the just
shall live by faith but if any man draw
back my soul shall have no pleasure in
him listen y'all if any man draw back
draw back from what draw back from
Christ who is lifted up on the cross
drawing us to
him and I if I be lifted up will draw
all men unto me well the just live by
faith what does that mean they are being
drawn to Christ by faith and they are
obeying and they are trusting in his
word by faith not by sight but if any
man draw back man Christ is drawing me
but I'm drawing back because I don't
believe the word because I don't trust
his
word as we behold Christ's courage and
boldness in his sacrifice we are drawn
to him by faith we we learn to trust his
word we learn to live by faith and not
by sight because that picture of a
serpent tells us man that's a bad thing
but by faith we know n that's
Jesus that's Jesus not only beloved does
he give us power over death not only
does he give us power over life not only
does he give us power over sight but
beloved he will grant us go to the
screen power over
hate he will give us that's the seven
brand candles the fire of God beloved
Song of Solomon chapter 8 tells us or or
John 15:13 says greater love has no man
in this that a man laid down his life
for his friends beloved that is love
that is the fire of the
Gospel listen listen
listen ssal of Solomon Chapter 8:6 set
me as a seal upon thine heart as a seal
upon thine are for love is strong as
death jealousy is as cruel as a grave
the Cs thereof are CS of fire which has
a most vem flame many Waters cannot
quench love beloved listen the more we
behold Christ on the cross we see a
picture of the fiery love of God and not
only do we begin to exercise this power
over the fear of death this power over
our lives this power over of over sight
versus Faith this power
we also get this Power of Love a burning
fiery love we get power over coldness
power over lukewarmness are y'all
following
me God is literally showing us how the
cross
works we lose P we lose Fe we lose we
get power over the fear of separation
from God the Bible tells us for God has
not given us the spirit of fear but of
power and of of love and of a sound
mind we no longer fear being separated
from God the altar of incense is there
to show us that if we call out to God he
will not forsake us we don't have to
fear being cut off we don't have to fear
of being separated from God we have a
boldness because we see what Jesus did
on the cross for us secures our
salvation and beloved we get power
over sin that law of God found in the
Ark of the Covenant we get power over
sin because we see man this is what put
Jesus on the cross it was the it was
these these things described in the law
put Christ on the cross and if I like
those things then I am I
am I am
supporting in a negative since the death
of Jesus if these things kill Jesus and
I love these things then that means I
would be ready to kill Jesus
myself are y'all catching
this if sin killed Jesus and I love
sin then I love the thing that killed
that caused the death of
Jesus now how would that make you
feel is somebody love the thing that put
you to
death as we behold Christ on the cross
we get power over sin because we begin
to hate it beloved why because it put
our Lord to death and this is why Jesus
said if you love me keep my
Commandments if you love me keep my
Commandments listen
y'all
we also get power over
unforgiveness isn't that be The Mercy
Seat as we behold the Cross of Christ
these articles of furniture are showing
us here's exactly what happens the more
you Behold the Lamb of God which takes
away the sin of the world your Sanctuary
becomes cleansed why because you learn
to hate righteous to hate uh uh uh
iniquity you learn to love righteousness
and you become transformed so that you
are a mirror reflecting the
righteousness of God not in your own
power there's no light in you the light
that is coming out of you is light that
has that is being reflected through you
and that cannot happen unless you
become that
mirror that is
focused on the cross of
Calvary Malachi CH 3 verse one Malachi
3:1 he shall sit as a refiner and
purifier of silver he shall purify the
sons of Levi and purge them as gold and
silver that they may offer unto the Lord
an offering in righteousness and second
or Titus Chapter 2: 13 the verse 13 the
Bible says looking for the Blessed hope
and the Glorious appearing of the great
God and our Savior Jesus Christ who gave
himself for us that he might redeem us
from all
iniquity and purify unto him self A
peculiar people zealous of Good
Works here's what I need yall to
understand when we talk about this this
this Everlasting gospel that is to go
into the whole world beloved it's the
same message from the very beginning of
time it's only that at this time it's
now more
urgent as a church beloved yes we are
called to uplift the law of God to
show everybody's a sinner everybody is
condemned that's the purpose of lifting
up the law of God including the Sabbath
which reveals listen if you're not will
to keep the Sabbath it reveals that you
want to trust in your what you think is
right versus depending upon the plainly
stated word of God so all the
Commandments are designed to do is to
show us how lost we
are not how righteous we are how lost we
are a and to take away any part of the
law is to give you an inaccurate picture
of just how lost you are and if you if
if you have an inaccurate picture of
just how lost you are you will end up
having an inaccurate picture of the
depth of the Salvation that is being
provided for us so as a church beloved
we have a mission to go out to the world
let them know hey this is the full law
of God this is how Wicked Man kind
really
is but once that's done beloved what do
we do what do we say so now you got to
keep the law no no no now focus on the
Lamb of God and if you focus on the Lamb
of God and his sacrifice for us in light
of the full picture of the law of God
you will begin to see and understand and
and experience the true
[Music]
gospel our message is very simple
beloved Behold the Lamb of God it's the
same message John the Baptist preached
Behold the Lamb of God if we
could go to the screen go to the
screen will not our church members keep
their eyes fixed on a crucified and
Risen Savior in whom their hopes of
eternal life are centered this is our
message the Everlasting gospel yeah
that's it right there the third Angel's
message that's it right there this is
our message justification by faith
justification by beholding the Lamb of
God this is our message our argument our
Doctrine our Doctrine Yes Y'all our
Doctrine our warning to the impenitent
our encouragement for The Sorrowing the
hope of every believer if we can awaken
an interest in men's Minds that that
will cause them to fix their eyes on
Christ we may step
aside and ask them only to continue to
fix their eyes upon the Lamb of God he
whose Eyes Are Fixed On Jesus will will
will not of their own power but
reactionary righteousness reflection
righteousness will why because they
become mirrors mirrors reflecting the
glory of God will leave all will die to
selfishness will believe in all the word
of God which is so gloriously and
wonderfully exalted in Christ
will Beloved the end time mission of
this church is to become
mirrors not mirrors of the law which
only point to condemnation that's the
purpose of the law it's to show us how
Wicked we really
are but the purpose of the church the
purpose of the of God's end time Church
beloved yet it's to it's to say look at
the law look how Wicked we are but
Behold the Lamb of God in the context of
the law Behold the Lamb of God and how
he can deliver you from the condemn
Behold the Lamb of God he will
change the contents of your book he he
will cleanse the temple from the record
of
sin but to do
that to have the Venom the sins removed
from the temple cleansed you've got to
behold the
cross what is my
appeal is it's very practical and very
simple number
one I want you to take
2024 to
start 2024 my entire
focus is going to be on the Lamb of
God I'm going to live this year under
the model Behold the Lamb of God when I
pray Lord teach me to Behold the Lamb of
God when teach me Lord to focus on
calvary's Cross like I have never
focused before and in so doing Lord I'm
going to pray I
pray that the changes that I've always
wanted to see in my life that those
things are going to begin to happen
because of your
glory because of your
power so my work Lord I cannot heal
myself
the only only thing I can do is look to
you and now you understand looking to
you doesn't mean hey are you going to do
something looking to you means let me
focus and study that amazing sacrifice
of love that took place at
Calvary help me to become a
mirror of your
glory if that's your desire put that one
in the chat Lord Make me a mirac mirror
make me a mirror make me a mirror make
me a
mirror before we pray I'm going to I'm
going to I'm going to appeal I'm going
to appeal if there's anyone who is
watching right now and you're like okay
I need to give my life to
Christ maybe you walked away from the
church maybe maybe you were like this is
too overwhelming and I can't do this cuz
I have tried and tried and tried and
tried and tried to be righteous I've
tried and I give up can't do
it yeah you can't do
it but today you're saying okay if
that's what it takes I can do that I can
look I can do that isn't that amazing
God just asks us to look that's it
salvation is is is is simply if we will
just look then you'll live you look I'll
take care of the
rest and me taking care of the rest is
going to result in Act action in
reactionary righteousness not hey I'm
not I I'm already righteous I'm good to
God no no no you are going to be living
out praise
God praise God for how simple God has
made it you see how the devil is complic
devil is out there telling people oh the
law of God has done away with so that he
can minimize the sacrifice of Christ on
the cross so that he can
minimize the depth of that sacrifice it
is not until we see the Grandeur of the
law that can we we can begin to rightly
appreciate the Grandeur of the sacrifice
you
all we got a mission I don't care who
you are God has called you to be a part
of this mission of reflecting the glory
of God make me a mirror make me a mirror
make me a mirror reflecting Your Love
dear Jesus heavenly father I want to
thank you for everyone that is
responding to this appeal right now I
want to thank you for those who have
left and are coming back because they
are now getting a better picture they've
gotten a better picture today of what it
means to F to Behold the Lamb of God
please
Lord forgive us for seeking to heal
ourselves forgive us for seeking to
force righteousness in instead of having
reactionary reflection
righteousness Lord
please work with us work through us work
through
US
Lord that we may grow into your image
and into your likeness and we are told
that when the church reflects your
character then you will come so Lord
You're simply waiting for us to become a
church Church of
mirrors a church of mirrors reflecting
your character reflecting the light of
your glory around the world may this
happen may we be a part of this Lord is
our prayer thank you Lord for
answering because we ask it in the
precious name of Jesus Amen and
[Music]
amen